{
    "seeSaw":
    [
        {
            "question": "If one side weight is 12kg (left) and the other side is 7kg (right), how much more weight is required so as to balance the see saw and on which side?",
            "option_1": "5kg left",
            "option_2": "10kg left",
            "option_3": "5kg right",
            "option_4": "10kg right",
            "correct": 3
        },

        {
            "question": "If Rahul and Kabir are sitting on a see saw and f Rahul leaves then in which direction will Kabir move ?",
            "option_1": "Insufficient information",
            "option_2": "Will remain stationary",
            "option_3": "Upwards",
            "option_4": "Downwards",
            "correct": 4
        },

        {
            "question": "See-Saw explains which law?",
            "option_1": "Conservation of Mass",
            "option_2": "Conservation of Torque",
            "option_3": "Conservation of Rotation",
            "option_4": "Coservation of Gravity",
            "correct": 2
        },

        {
            "question": "What is the point called where see saw is balanced?",
            "option_1": "Radix",
            "option_2": "Center",
            "option_3": "Pivot",
            "option_4": "None of the above",
            "correct": 3
        },

        {
            "question": "If left side weighs 50kg and the other side is 60kg, in which direction should the pivot be moved so as to balance the see saw?",
            "option_1": "Left",
            "option_2": "Right",
            "option_3": "Should be kept stationary",
            "option_4": "Can not be determined",
            "correct": 1
        }

    ],

    "trundlewheel":
    [
        {
            "question": "What does a trundle wheel measure?",
            "option_1": "Distance",
            "option_2": "Angle",
            "option_3": "Volume",
            "option_4": "Area",
            "correct": 1
        },

        {
            "question": "If the wheel measures 200 cm in one complete rotation, how much distance will be covered in 108 degrees?",
            "option_1": "10 cm",
            "option_2": "20 cm",
            "option_3": "30 cm",
            "option_4": "40 cm",
            "correct": 3
        },

        {
            "question": "Who invented the measuring wheel?",
            "option_1": "John Metcalf",
            "option_2": "Issac Newton",
            "option_3": "Albert Einstein",
            "option_4": "Archmidies",
            "correct": 1
        },

        {
            "question": "What is the circumference of an ideal trundle wheel?",
            "option_1": "50 cm",
            "option_2": "100 cm",
            "option_3": "150 cm",
            "option_4": "200 cm",
            "correct": 2
        },

        {
            "question": "If the wheel measures 1 meter in one complete rotation, what will be the angle rotated by the wheel to travel 350 cm?",
            "option_1": "19<sup>o</sup>",
            "option_2": "20<sup>o</sup>",
            "option_3": "21<sup>o</sup>",
            "option_4": "22<sup>o</sup>",
            "correct": 4
        }

    ],

    "solarlight":
    [
        {
            "question": "Which sensor is used in solar security light system?",
            "option_1": "PIR sensor",
            "option_2": "IR sensor",
            "option_3": "Ultrasonic Sensor",
            "option_4": "Relay",
            "correct": 1
        },

        {
            "question": "In which battery does solar panel store energy?",
            "option_1": "Li-Cd battery",
            "option_2": "Li-Ion battery",
            "option_3": "Hydrogen cell",
            "option_4": "Ni-Cd battery",
            "correct": 2
        },

        {
            "question": "In this circuit, the principle is to convert light energy to electrical energy.",
            "option_1": "True",
            "option_2": "False",
            "option_3": "Can not be determined",
            "option_4": "Need more information",
            "correct": 1
        },

        {
            "question": "How much angle can the sensor sense(in degrees)?",
            "option_1": "45",
            "option_2": "90",
            "option_3": "120",
            "option_4": "180",
            "correct": 3
        },

        {
            "question": "If we use 5 LED in a circuit and each LED consumes 20mW of power, then how much will be the maximum power consumption?",
            "option_1": "20mW",
            "option_2": "4mW",
            "option_3": "100mW",
            "option_4": "200mW",
            "correct": 3
        }
        
    ],

    "ultrasonic":
    [
        {
            "question": "What does ultrasonic sensor measure?",
            "option_1": "Time",
            "option_2": "Distance",
            "option_3": "Speed",
            "option_4": "Torque",
            "correct": 2
        },

        {
            "question": "Ultrasonic sound travels faster than the audible sound?",
            "option_1": "True",
            "option_2": "False",
            "option_3": "Maybe",
            "option_4": "Don't know",
            "correct": 1
        },

        {
            "question": "Which is the input pin in the sensor?",
            "option_1": "Trig",
            "option_2": "Echo",
            "option_3": "Input",
            "option_4": "Output",
            "correct": 1
        },

        {
            "question": "Which is the output pin ?",
            "option_1": "Trig",
            "option_2": "Echo",
            "option_3": "Input",
            "option_4": "Output",
            "correct": 2
        }
    ]

}